It appears that you're the last one.
（テル）
どうやら お前で最後のようだな
（傷４）
クソ！　ガキどもが調子に乗るな！
Damn it! You damn brats...
Who do you think you are?!
（星野(ほしの)武史(たけし)）
砂埃(すなぼこり)旋風！
Dust Cyclone!
Flamethrower!
（朝日(あさひ) 豪(ごう)）
火炎放射！
Combo Attack! Telekinetic Pillar of Flame!
（武史と豪）
合体奥義！　念動火柱！
Don't underestimate me! This is nothing—
見くびるな！
この程度の威力で… ぶはっ！
（傷４）
ぐはっ… うっ…
（テル）
よくやった ２人とも
Good job, you two.
強くなったね
You've gotten stronger.
We've been practicing every day.
（豪）
毎日 練習してたもんな
It's all thanks to your guidance, Teru-san.
（武史）
テルさんの指導のおかげだぜ！
Thank you for helping us, Takeuchi-san.
嶽内(たけうち)さんも助かりました
No need to thank me.
I left the organization as well.
（嶽内(たけうち)）
礼には及ばぬ
私も組織とは対立した立場だ
I acted like I betrayed you so we could
pull off a splendid surprise attack.
（寺蛇(てらだ)）
裏切ったフリして華麗な不意打ち！
機転を利かせた寺蛇様に
よ～く感謝するんだな
You better be grateful for me
and my peerless wit.
What? H-Huh? I can't move...
なんだよ？　って あれ？
体が動かん
（テル）
海斗(かいと)君！
Kaito-kun.
Lie-Detection Telepathy!
（白鳥海斗(しらとりかいと)）
嘘発見テレパシー
（海斗）
ああ 大丈夫
まだ裏切ってないみたい
It's okay. He hasn't betrayed us yet.
“まだ”ってどういうことだ！
What do you mean, "yet"?!
（嶽内）
で これからどうする？
So what are we going to do now?
Reigen-san said we didn't have to fight,
霊幻さんは
戦わなくていいって言ってたけど
but I disagree.
そうもいかないよね
We're going to take our city back.
この町を取り返すんだ
(Get ready, wake your psyche up, MOB!)
(Get ready, dig your anger up, MOB!)
(Get ready!)
Coming down, could you fill your satisfaction?
You're a MOB. Can't you feel your own frustration?
You're a MOB. What do you want to be?
Wear your overflowing emotions on your sleeve and break it down.
What do you see once you go beyond your limits?
(99.9! 99.9!)
The mysterious percentage.
Cryin' my life, cryin' my psyche,
cryin' my heart in such commonplaces!
Is that your ideal? Is that your mind?
It all begins when it hits 100.
The MOB is alive. The MOB is high.
The MOB is staying frustrated, aren't you?
Is that your ideal? Is that your mind? Right now...
Your life is your own.
(Get ready, wake your psyche up, MOB!)
Mob Psycho
(Get ready, dig your anger up, MOB!)
(Get ready, wake your psyche up, MOB!)
(Get ready!)
Guidance
~Psychic Sensor~
（鈴木(すずき)）
犬どもが
少しの間 放っておいただけで―
You pathetic dogs...
You've forgotten how terrifying your owner
can be because I left you alone for a bit.
（鈴木）
飼い主の恐ろしさを
忘れてしまったようだな
ショウが来た
Sho is here.
（影山(かげやま) 律(りつ)）
よし 行こう
Okay, let's go.
Say, Ritsu.
（ショウ）
なあ 律
お前 なんで
そんなに協力的なんだ？
Why are you being so cooperative?
君の境遇を
ひと事とは思えなかったからだ
Because your situation wasn't
completely unrelatable.
There are times when I worry what'd happen
if Nii-san went berserk with his powers.
（律）
もし兄さんが
あの力を持って暴走したら…
そんな不安が よぎるときがある
鈴木 君の父親は暴走している
And Suzuki, your father is
going berserk right now.
あれを止められるのは君しかいない
You're the only one who can stop him.
Yeah! I'll show you that I can finish this!
おう 見せてやるよ
スカッとする決着をよ！
おっ 出たな 島崎(しまざき)！
There you are,
Shimazaki!
I can tell at a glance...
（律）
あれは見て分かる　かなり強い
He's really strong!
He's a teleporter that can
read his enemy's movements.
（ショウ）
あいつは
敵の動きを読むテレポーターだ
まずは俺が…
First, I'll—
You go on ahead.
（律）
先に行け
I'll keep him occupied.
あの男は僕が引き受ける
You can't deal with him alone.
ありゃ １人じゃ無理だぜ
He's one of the strongest
in the whole organization.
組織の中でも最強の一角だ
And that's exactly why.
（律）
だからこそだ
In return, promise me that
you'll stop your father.
そのかわり父親を止めろ　必ずだ
約束するぜ
やっぱり お前がいてよかった
I promise. I'm glad to have you around.
Go!
（律）
行け！
He got away?
（律）
逃げられた？
ハア… ハア…
（律）
鈴木を追う気はないのか？
He doesn't intend to follow Suzuki?
（島崎）後ろですよ
（律）ハッ
I'm over here.
I'd appreciate it if you
wouldn't resist so much.
（島崎）
あまり抵抗しないでもらえると
ありがたいのですが…
I don't exactly like beating on weaklings.
弱者をなぶる趣味は ないんで
（律）
弱者は あなたもだ！
You're just as weak!
Oh? And who are you comparing me to?
（島崎）
ほう
一体 何と比べているんですかね
I should've taken him out
before it got to this point.
（ショウ）
本当は こうなる前に
やっつけるべきだった
I'd just been powerless to do anything
but sit back and watch...
今まで力不足だったから
黙って見てるしかなかったが…
（羽鳥(はとり)）
そこまでだ
This is it for you.
Such a shame. You managed to get this far...
ここまで来れたのに残念だったな
But now, you have to deal with me.
僕が相手だ
My dad is using his powers for evil,
（ショウ）
おやじは“力”を悪用するが―
but I'm going to use my powers
to show him what's right!
俺は この力で正義を示す！
I'm going to end this!
決着をつけてやる！
（モブ）
ひどい　超能力でこんなことを…
How awful. Someone used
psychic powers to do this?
That's the enemy base.
（エクボ）
あそこがテロリストの拠点だ
霊幻(れいげん)たちも向かってるはずだぜ
Reigen and the others should
be heading over, too.
Hey, there's still some brat here.
Did he wait too long to run away?
（構成員）
おう？　ガキがいるぜ
逃げ遅れか？
Whoo! Got us some dinner.
（構成員）
今日の晩飯 ゲット～
So they're pillaging the area.
略奪か
（モブ）
そこ 律と行ったことがある
I've gone there with Ritsu before.
Return what you took from the store.
Stealing is a crime.
店に戻しなよ　犯罪だよ
You're supposed to be adults.
（モブ）
まして大人なのに…
Who the hell are you?
なんだ このガキ
（構成員）
ギャハハハハ
This town belongs to us now.
（構成員）
この町は もう俺らのものなんだ
ハハハハッ やめてやれよ
トラウマになるぞ
Yo, stop. You're gonna traumatize him.
Stop messing around with your powers.
“力”で いたずらするな
そんなふうに使うな
Don't use them like this.
やめろ
Stop.
I-Is this kid a natural esper?
こ… このガキ
ナチュラルなエスパーか
Could you guys manufacture this can?
（モブ）
この缶
あんたらに これが作れるか？
Huh?
このサンドイッチに
挟まってる野菜を育てられるか？
Could you actually grow
the vegetables in this sandwich?
Could you fix that glass door you just broke?
さっき壊したガラスのドア
自分で直せるか？
Could your powers help you hit upon the idea
of giving out a freebie for a lucky draw?
“当たりが出たら もう１個”
なんてアイデア―
超能力で思いつくか？
The hell are you trying to say?
何が言いてえ？
You guys are making a huge mistake,
（モブ）
あんたたちは
“力”が使えるくらいで―
自分が大きな存在だと
勘違いしてるだけだ
thinking you're special
just because of your powers.
人に助けられて生きてるってこと
You should realize that you're only able to
survive thanks to the help of others.
それに気付いたほうが いいよ
You fool! You can make anyone submit
to you as long as you have power!
（構成員）
バカめ！
“力”さえあれば
他者を屈服させられる！
One last thing... Don't use your
physic powers against others.
（モブ）
もう１つ 教える
超能力を人に向けるな
If you don't have anyone
who can give you that advice,
それを注意してくれる人が
いないのなら―
I'll do it.
僕がやる
Holy crap, he's pissed. I'm gonna get back.
（エクボ）
スゲえ怒ってる　離れとこ
An attack by the enemy?
（構成員たち）
敵襲か？　集合しろ！
Gather everyone up!
Well, well...
Looks like we had quite the stray show up.
とんでもない野良の能力者が
いたものだな
（構成員）
峯岸さん！
Minegishi-san!
I'll take him down.
You guys back me up.
（峯岸）
僕がしとめるから 補助よろしく
こいつらは
僕が与えるエネルギーによって―
These will grow as much as I'd like
if I give them my power,
いくらでも成長する
and multiply as much as I'd like.
そして いくらでも増える
You can do it, too?
（峯岸）
君にもできるのか？
You don't really like plants, do you?
（モブ）
あんたは
別に植物が好きじゃないんだね
That's right. They're merely tools.
（峯岸）
うん　ただの道具だよ
Go! Drop him!
（構成員）
いけ！　落とせ！
Help Minegishi-san out!
峯岸さんに加勢しろ！
Hit him with your telekinesis!
（構成員）
念動力をぶつけるんだ！
（律）ぐはっ！
（落ちた音）
（島崎）
長いものには巻かれるものだよ
It's better to bend than break.
You should join our side.
君もこっち側につけばいい
（律）
それは楽かもしれないけど
楽しくないな
That might be easier, but it's no fun.
（島崎）
う～ん もう力の差は
分かったはずだけど―
You should see the difference
in our abilities by now.
You sure you won't change your mind
if I hurt you a bit more?
これ以上 痛い目に遭っても
その考えは変わらないのかな？
I always wanted to be able
to use psychic powers.
（律）
ずっと超能力を使いたいと
思っていた
But now that I've finally awakened to
these powers, I finally understand...
でも この力に覚醒してから
やっと分かった
To shed blood, sweat, and tears
in order to live a fun life...
楽しく生きるために
悩み 汗をかき 涙を流す
What I really wanted was
that kind of wholehearted devotion.
僕が本当に手に入れたかったのは
そのひたむきさだったんだ
I won't let anyone take away
my ability to live a fun life!
楽しく生きたい
そこだけは譲れない
うちには
向いてないかもしれませんね
Guess you might not be a good fit, after all.
In that case, I'll just...
ならば ここで…
Ow...
痛い
I managed to land a hit for the first time!
（誇山(こやま)）
初めてヒットしたぜ！
My, my, you're far more
resilient than I'd imagined.
（島崎）
いやはや 想定以上のしぶとさ
（桜威(さくらい)）
さっきは よくもやってくれたな
We need to repay you for
what you did earlier.
ドブネズミ改め ゴキブリですね
I guess you're not sewer rats.
You're cockroaches.
（槌屋(つちや)）
組織にいたころとは違う
We've changed since we were in Claw.
（邑機(むらき)）
自立しようとする意志の力を
持った私たちは手ごわいぞ
Now that we want independence,
we're far more resilient.
The results won't change,
no matter how many times you try.
（島崎）
何度やっても同じですよ
（テル）
強がるなよ　焦ってるくせに
Don't act so tough.
We know you're panicking.
Even if you can read our moves,
（テル）
いくら先読みができても
数が多ければ限界が来るはずだ
you should hit your limit
with so many people.
I'll be getting my revenge!
リベンジさせてもらうよ
Takeuchi!
（槌屋）
嶽内！
Tsuchiya!
（嶽内）
槌屋！
Not happening!
（誇山）
させねえよ！
（寺蛇）
ぐはっ
Aren't you going to shoot?
（島崎）
撃たないのですか？
（櫻威）
ぐはっ
I don't think capture tactics
will be of much use.
（島崎）
拘束の類いはムダだと思いますが…
I told you...
（島崎）
言ったでしょう？
何人いても同じだと
Cleaning
The result won't change, no matter
how many of you there are.
ほう
（テル）
手数(てかず)だ！
Attack more!
The more moves we make,
手数があれば
移動先を予測して追い詰められる！
we can figure out where
he'll teleport and finish him!
They're far more capable than
those people in the division...
（モブ）
支部にいた人たちとはレベルが…
Don't stop, Shigeo!
止まるな 茂夫(しげお)！
All right! He's panicking!
Let's hit him some more!
よし 焦ってるぞ！　もっとだ！
（魔津尾(まつお)）
苦戦してるみたいね
Looks like you're having some trouble.
（モブ）
あなたは…
You're...
I wouldn't mind lending you my support.
私がサポートしてあげてもいいわよ
さあ 行きなさい！
Now, go!
It's Matsuo, the evil-spirit user!
（構成員）
悪霊使いの魔津尾だ！
He's gonna send all kinds of monsters at us!
（構成員）
化け物が なだれ込んでくるぞ！
I'd appreciate it if you
wouldn't underestimate me...
（峯岸）
見くびらないでほしいな
（魔津尾）うっ
（モブ）魔津尾さん！
Matsuo-san!
（構成員）
何だ この小瓶？
What's this small bottle?
Talk about bad taste.
趣味 悪(わり)いな
（魔津尾）
ダ… ダメ！　それだけは…
N-No, anything but that!
Even I can't control it! Don't touch it!
私の手にも余る　触るな！
You dumbass! We have Minegishi-san!
バ～カ！
俺たちには
峯岸さんが いるんだよ！
Wh-What? Why's everyone falling...
なっ 何だ？　なぜ倒れ… あっ…
（最上(もがみ)啓示(けいじ)）
コオオオ…
What... is that?
あれは 何だ？
Mogami-san!
（モブ）
最上さん？　マズい
This isn't good.
何だ これは？
What is that?
（最上）
蠱毒(こどく)の次は―
So, after the poison jar, you now want me
to devour a horde of espers...
（最上）
超能力者の群れを食えということか
You're such lowly creatures...
質の低い者たちだ
Wh-What the hell is that?!
な… 何だ これは？
My plants aren't listening to me!
（峯岸）
植物の制御が利かない！
Mob Psycho
Winner
Wi
Stop!
（モブ）
やめろ！
（最上）
なぜ止める？
Why are you trying to stop me?
見ていたが―
I've been watching, and none of
these insects deserve to live.
生かしておいてもしょうがない
クズどもだ
There are humans that never change.
恩を売ったところで
変わらない人間もいる
But... they might be able to change!
でも 変われるかもしれない
Promise that you won't do
anything bad ever again!
もう悪いことしないって
約束してくれ！
ああ 約束する　助けてくれ
I promise... Spare me...
See?!
ほら！
What if he's just lying so he can survive?
（最上）
その場しのぎの嘘(うそ)だったら？
Are you going to watch over them
until they've reformed?
こいつらが更生するまで
君が面倒を見るのか？
You think you can keep an eye on them forever?
監視し続けられると？
Well... no.
（モブ）
それは できないよ
But we need to have faith in one another
in order to get through life.
でも 人が生きるには
信じるしかないんだ
If we can't do that,
we'll never get anywhere.
それが できなくちゃ
何も始まらないだろう？
I'd expect nothing less from you.
（最上）
君らしいな
But there are things that can't
be solved with mere kindness.
だが 優しさだけでは
解決できないこともある
It's also necessary to be
hard on people at times.
ときに人に厳しくするのも必要だ
If you can do that, you will be invincible,
Kageyama Shigeo-kun.
そうなれば君は誰にも負けない
影山茂夫君
Did Mogami disappear
for good this time, or...?
（エクボ）
今度こそ 最上は消滅したのか？
それとも…
Be hard on people, huh?
“人に厳しく”か
I'm not very good at that.
苦手だな
（ショウ）
ここまで来たぜ
I'm here now. Claw is finished!
“爪”は もう終わりだ
（鈴木）
ショウ もっと別のやり方が
あったんじゃないか？
Sho, there must've been a
better way of doing this.
We're family.
親子なんだぞ
What? Now you want to act like a father?
お？　今更 父親ヅラかよ
You never cared about a damn thing I said.
俺の意見なんか
聞いた試しもねえくせに
You should've attacked while
playing the obedient son.
（鈴木）
従順な息子のフリをして
襲撃すればよかっただろう
ふんっ
（鈴木）
これ以上 邪魔をするんじゃない
Don't get in my way any further.
It took me twenty years to get here.
ここまで20年かかったんだぞ
（ショウ）
ざま～見やがれ！
Serves you right! I've ruined
those twenty years for you!
その20年を台なしにしてやったぜ！
I'm just as strong as the Ultimate 5 now!
俺は もう
“５超(ごちょう)”並みに強くなった！
Fight me, man to man!
てめえとも まともに戦える…
Don't make me laugh.
笑わせるな
（鈴木）親を見くびるなよ
（ショウ）うりぇ！
Never look down on your father.
（ショウ）
近づくだけで発動する
クソ強力なバリア？
A stupidly powerful barrier that
activates when I try to get close...
それが てめえの本当の能力か？
Is that your true power?
In that case...
それなら！
Damn it... He's mocking me!
クソ！　ナメやがって
These techniques are mere child's play.
（鈴木）
こんな技術は遊びにすぎん
I thought you would've grown
a little more than that.
もう少し成長しているものだと
思っていたぞ
Oh? You've learned how to mess with
the refraction factor of light?
ほう 光の屈折率を
いじれるようになったか
This is my trump card!
（ショウ）
これが俺の取って置きだ
Here's the energy I've saved up
over three months...
３か月ためたエネルギー
Charge Bomb!
チャージボム！
Hell, yeah! Justice prevails!
よっしゃ～！　正義は勝つ！
I'm so sorry. I wouldn't have taken a
bathroom break if I'd known this'd happen.
（芹沢(せりざわ)）
すみません
自分がトイレに行ってる間に…
That's fine.
（鈴木）
問題ない
ちょっとした反抗期なだけだ
My son's just going through
his rebellious phase.
Being a bad boy again?
（芹沢）
またグレてるのかい？
You'll never turn out to be
a decent adult like that.
そんなんじゃ
ろくな大人になれないぞ
Screw you! That was three
months' worth of energy!
クソが！　今のは３か月分だぞ
Let's stop fighting and happily
take over the world together.
（芹沢）
ケンカは この辺にして
仲良く世界征服しようよ
Don't bother.
余計な世話を焼くな
I can see why Sho would disagree with this.
ショウが反対する理由も
分からなくはない
失敗を恐れているんだろう？
You fear this plan will fail, don't you?
You don't know the outside world, after all.
お前は外の世界を知らないからな
The real reason I went around the world
私が世界を回った真の目的は―
was to see if world domination
would actually be realistic.
世界征服が現実にできるかどうか
見定めるためだ
But ultimately, I couldn't find a single
esper stronger than me in this world.
結果 世界に私より強い能力者は
誰一人 存在しなかった
最高の力を持っているのは私だ
I have the ultimate power.
And that gives you the right
to take over the world?
（ショウ）
イコール 世界を征服をできる
って答えになるのかよ
聞いたか 芹沢？
Did you hear that, Serizawa?
He's totally messed up in the head.
やっぱりこの男は どうかしてる！
社長　かっけえ
President...
You're so cool.
（ショウ）
くっ…
強力なバカが いちばんやっかいだ
Absolute idiots are the worst to deal with!
I'm impressed with your attack earlier.
（鈴木）
先ほどの攻撃は見直したぞ
The apple really doesn't
fall far from the tree.
やはり親子は似るものだな
一緒にすんな！　どこがだ？
Don't lump me in with you!
How am I anything like you?!
You said you were charging
up energy for three months?
（鈴木）
エネルギーを３か月ためたと
言っていたな
I have the same ability.
私も同じ能力を持っている
なに？
What?!
Didn't I tell you?
（鈴木）
話しただろう？
私は ここまでの準備に
20年かけたと
I spent twenty years preparing for this.
Don't tell me that the last twenty years
wasn't to gather all those troops...
（ショウ）
まさか その準備って
兵隊集めじゃなくて…
I guess it wouldn't hurt to show you
some of my twenty years...
（鈴木）
20年分 少し見せてやろうか？
（銃声）
（桜威）ぐはっ…
Why not give up already,
（島崎）
いいかげん諦めたらどうですか？
you poor souls the boss named the Scars?
ボスが“傷”と名付けた
かわいそうな者たち
Shut it!
（誇山）
クソ！
You're a goddamn coward that doesn't
have to guts to go against the boss!
てめえはボスに刃向かう度胸もねえ
腰抜けだろうが！
フッ… ボスが故意に残した
“傷”の本当の意味は“ペケ”
The real reason he named you "Scars"
is because you're all failures.
You were marked as damaged goods!
役に立たない欠陥品という
マークですよ
ナメやがって！
Screw you!
念動螺旋(らせん)！
Telekinetic Helix!
（島崎）
超能力者としての
基礎値の段階で―
（槌屋）
たああ！
As for the basics required of espers...
（島崎）
超能力者としての
基礎値の段階で―
あなたたちとは格が違うんですよ
we're on a entirely different level.
I'm saying this for your own good.
悪いことは言わない
諦めたほうがいい
You should just give up.
But that manhole cover had
some effect, didn't it?
（桜威）
だが さっきのマンホールは
効いたよな？
（律）
あっ テルさん！
Teru-san!
Yeah. It looks like attacks he didn't
detect actually work against him.
ああ 事前に感知してない攻撃は
効くのかも
He's the one who's been cornered here.
追い詰められてるのは
実は あっちのほうに違いない
フウ… 君は優秀だな
You're quite efficient.
（島崎）決めた
（テル）うっ！
Because of that,
I'll get rid of you first, once and for all.
まずは君を徹底的にたたく
ふん！
Not good. He's going to destroy him.
（槌屋）
マズいね　壊される
What can we do?
（律）
どうすればいいんだ？
そろそろ おしまいですね！
I believe it's time to end things.
Next, you'll come from behind!
（テル）
次は後ろ！
君…
You—
It might be convenient to be able
to read your opponents' moves,
（テル）
相手の動きを読めるのは
便利かもしれないけど―
but that also makes your moves monotonous.
あんたの動きも単調になるんだよ
You rely too much on your powers.
能力に頼り過ぎてる
Well, this is surprising.
（島崎）
驚きましたね
If we disregard the boss, I do have
the position as the world's greatest.
一応 ボスを除けば
世界一の自負があるのですが
There are people in this world
with powers you can't even fathom.
世の中には いるんだよ
想像も及ばない力を持つ人が
You're just an ordinary man.
Even I could defeat you.
あんたも凡人なんだな
どうやら僕でも倒せそうだ
Why y—
この… うっ！
You're right! It's when he's distracted!
（律）
やっぱり 気がそれた瞬間だ！
Nice, Little Bro!
（テル）
ナイスだ！　弟君！
（槌屋）
ふっ！　５発目！
Fifth Punch!
Super Destructive Energy Blast!
（嶽内）
超滅気功弾！
う～りゃ～！
I-I need to regain my...
（島崎）
た… 体勢を…
C-Concentrate...
（島崎）
くっ… 集中しろ 集中！
Concentrate. Concentrate and you'll
be able to figure everything out.
集中すれば全て分かる
Everyone here is an esper.
Cut everything else out.
この場にいる全員が超能力者
それ以外は一切 遮断！
Concentrate. Concentrate.
集中！　集中！
Mind's Eye!
マインズアイ！
Nothing you can do will
ever work on me again.
（島崎）
もう どんな手だても
私には通じません
ダメージや
本人でさえ知らないだろう弱点
Your injuries, the weaknesses
even you're not aware of,
and the fact that you can barely see now...
そのほとんどかすんだ目も
全てが手に取るように分かります
I can see through everything now.
It's too late to have any regrets.
後悔しても もう遅いですよ
What's the matter?
（テル）
どうした？
Something with tremendous
energy is heading this way.
（島崎）
何かが…
強大なエネルギーを持つ何かが
近づいてきている
Pretty sure that's my friend.
それは きっと僕の知人だな
I guess you finally woke up,
（テル）
やっと起きたんだね
影山君
Kageyama-kun.
（島崎）
フフフ… 面白い
How amusing.
Let's see whose abilities are greater!
（島崎）
果たしてどちらの能力が上か
勝負です！
フフフ…
正面から迎え撃ってあげましょう！
I'll face you head-on!
Self-Defense Rush!
（霊幻新隆(れいげんあらたか)）
正当防衛ラッシュ！
One of Reigen's special moves where,
（ナレーション）
厳密に正当防衛と言えるか
分からない際に とりあえず―
Self-Defense Rush
when he's unsure if it's really self-defense,
he yells out "self-defense" just in case.
“正当防衛”と叫んでおく
霊幻の必殺技である
（島崎）
ぐわ～！
Impossible! I couldn't sense him at all.
（島崎）
バカな　全く感知できなかった
何者だ？
Who is he?!
Reigen-san!
（テル）
霊幻さん！
Everyone, get up! The great master is here.
（邑機）
みんな 起きろ！
大先生が来てくれたぞ！
The great master? Don't tell me...
（島崎）
大先生？　まさか―
There's an esper who can actually
make his presence disappear?
虫の境地まで気配を消せる
エスパーが存在するのか？
What should I do? Should I withdraw?
どうする？　引くべきか？
Master, he's rather strong.
師匠 その人 かなり強いですよ
He's dangerous, so please step back.
危険だから離れてください
（霊幻）
おお モブ
無事だったか…
Oh, hey, Mob.
That boy from earlier and
this unknown esper...
（島崎）
さっきの少年に
得体の知れないエスパー
Just how many are there?
一体どれだけ…
大きな組織でもあるというのか？
Do they have some kind of huge organization?
More importantly, this kid...
is on a whole other level.
何より この少年―
桁(けた)違いだ
Yeah, I give up.
I don't stand a chance. I give.
やっぱり やめだ　割に合わない
降参します
（霊幻）
お？　えらくあっさりしてるな
Well, that was easy.
What happened to taking over the world?
世界征服の意気込みは
どこ行った？
The only one serious about that is the boss.
本気なのはボスだけですよ
I don't really care
as long as I get to have fun.
私は楽しければ何だっていいんです
As long as you get to have fun?
（モブ）
“楽しければいい”だって？
You disrupted the lives of
so many people just for that?
それで 多くの人に
迷惑をかけたのか？
You can't be serious.
ふざけるな
ひいっ
（寺蛇）
あっ 逃げやがった
He ran away!
（誇山）
チェッ 勝った気がしねえ
I don't feel like we won at all.
He might attack again.
また襲ってくるかもしれんな
No, I'm pretty sure he's been traumatized.
いや きっとヤツに
トラウマを植え付けた
I think he might've learned his place
and turned over a new leaf.
身の程を知って これから生き方を
直していくんじゃないかな
Nii-san.
（律）
兄さん
あっ 律！　大丈夫？
Ritsu! Are you okay?
Yeah. Mom and Dad are somewhere safe, too.
うん　父さん 母さんも
安全な場所にいるよ
I see. So it's just like
Dimple and Master said.
そっか
エクボや師匠の言ったとおりだ
We sure had one hell of a scare.
（エクボ）
俺様たちも肝を冷やしたな
Shut up.
（霊幻）
黙ってろよ
Now, then... I guess all we
have left is the last boss.
（テル）
さて 残るはラスボスだけかな
Hoshino-kun and the others should be
getting people to safety right about now.
星野君たちが
みんなを救出してるころだし―
Let's meet back up with them and attack.
合流して突入しよう
No.
（モブ）
ダメだよ
みんな ケガだらけじゃないか
You're all hurt.
I'll go alone.
僕１人で行くから
（テル）
なっ… 影山君
何を言ってるんだい？
K-Kageyama-kun! What are you talking about?!
僕も行くよ
仲間が先に突入してるんだ
I'll go, too! One of my
friends already went in!
（モブ）
ダメ
No.
This might be hard to hear,
but you'll just be in my way.
厳しいこと言うと足手まといなんだ
I'm sorry.
ごめん
"Being hard on people"...
（エクボ）
“人に厳しく”
So this is how Shigeo processed
what Mogami said to him.
最上の言葉を
茂夫なりに解釈した結果か
Dimple, I'm counting on you.
エクボ 頼むぞ
I know!
分かってるよ
I spilled a seed and lost sight of it
I'll find it using the color it's dyed in and watch it grow
It immediately returned to the palm of my hand
But it's still too light and too frail to reach for the skies
The world coldly drains away all the heat
The bright sunshine just isn't enough
The memories are closing off what lies ahead
Shake off their warmth and set off into the distance
If I let it wither, it'd be over just like that
But my hope just doesn't fade away
You're not scared to do this on your own?
（エクボ）
お前 １人で怖くないのか？
Of course I'm scared.
（モブ）
怖いよ
But having someone else get hurt
scares me even more.
でも これ以上
誰かが傷つけられるほうが怖い
I'm sure I'll be able
to figure something out.
まあ なんとかやってみるよ
（エクボ）
ヤベえな
Crap... I'm trying to take advantage
of him while he's still a kid,
ガキのうちに
うまく取り入ろうってのに
but Shigeo's going to become
an adult before I know it.
茂夫のヤツ
うかうかしてると大人になっちまう
Are you in middle school?
Damn... You're still a kid.
（芹沢）
君 中学生？
嫌だな　まだ子供じゃないか
This is a really bad time.
特に今はタイミングが悪いんだよね
Would you kindly leave?
お願いだから帰ってくれないかな？
Mob finally infiltrates the enemy's base.
（霊幻）
ついに 敵の根城に乗り込んだモブ
Can he get past Serizawa
and make it to the boss?
芹沢を退け
ボスにたどり着けるのか？
そのころ
息子のショウを倒したボスは―
Meanwhile, the boss, who just defeated
his son, Sho, shows his true identity.
真の姿を明らかにする
次回「モブサイコ100 Ⅱ」
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 II Episode 12:
第12話「社会復帰戦　友情」
"The Battle for Social Rehabilitation
~Friendship~."
The serious option C involves
Blu-rays, manga volumes, and events!
The Battle for Social Rehabilitation
~Friendship~
本気のＣコースだと
ブルーレイ 単行本 イベント